The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
War God Shrine
Burning Fire country
The formation is activating.
Here they come.
Look !
They're back.
They're finally back !
Xu Si
War God Shrine disciple
Late stage Foundation Establishment
Welcome back Senior Brothers, Sister Sister.
How was the harvest this time ?
Did you find any powerful artifacts ?
Tell us how it went !
Good, you guys endured the trial of the Foreign Battlefield.
The three of you have greatly improved your cultivation.
Huo Hongfei
War God Shrine Elder
Early stage Core Formation
It's a shame so few of you returned.
Elder,
Junior Brother Ma Liang is still inside.
The situation was critical
so he told the us to leave first.
He’ll catch up soon.
Junior Brother Ma Liang survived ?
Ma Liang isn’t dead !?
Silence.
Were you hoping for Ma Liang's death ?
Is this how your master taught you !?
Don’t worry Junior Sister,
Junior Brother Ma Liang spent 50 years in the Foreign Battlefield
so his temperament has changed.
I don't think
that he will bother you anymore.
Zhou An
War God Shrine disciple
Late stage Foundation Establishment
What’s there to fear ?
If he dares to harass you again,
I’ll handle it.
This is…
such a powerful cold aura...
This aura…
Is this Ma Liang ?
Disciple Ma Liang
pays respects to Elder Huo.
I'm glad you made it back.
Come with me.
Disciple has urgent matters to deal with.
I'll come after I'm done dealing with them.
Here are the items I collected over these 50 years.
The artifacts were destroyed
so only these materials remain.
This kid exudes an unusually cold aura...
I should report this to the Sect Leader.
Let's hide here, Ah Niu won’t find us.
Found you !
An Immortal ! An Immortal !
My mother said that
the volcanoes of the Burning Fire country would've errupted long ago
if they weren't sealed by the Immortals !
I want to become an Immortal too !
Kids, come back for dinner.
Okay !
We're going home !
Mom,
I saw an Immortal today !
Really ?
I need to find a place to cultivate...
I'm glad I held out this long...
Let's first inspect this body.
So this is my Sea of Consciousness.
This red lightning must be the Ji Realm refined by the Law of the World.
Since it resisted the Law of the World,
it must be powerful.
The Ji Realm can actually awaken the Heaven Defying Bead and my sword ?
If this Ji Realm Divine Sense were to fill my Sea of Counsciousness,
even the Law of the World would pale before me.
They must have
outstanding form and spirit !
Father… Mother…
It’s me… I’m Tie Zhu.
Do you still recognize me ?
Once I recover,
I’ll find my way back to the country of Zhao.
I'll deal with Teng Huayuan...
Blood for blood.
Ge Yang and Xu Hao’s bags of holding
had this piece of refined iron.
It's top quality.
I don’t know anything about artifact crafting
so I can't make a new sword.
This will have to do.
1 year later
Senior,
This body is already Middle stage Foundation Establishment.
With the Ji Realm,
I can defeat any Foundation Establishment cultivator.
I'm even confident in facing
Early stage Core Formation.
What is this wood element spiritual energy ?
Burning Gold Mountain Range
Zhou Gang
Corpse Sect disciple
Middle stage Foundation Establishment
Junior Sister An, is this your first time picking Burning Gold Fruits ?
Yes
An Zi
Corpse Sect disciple
Middle stage Foundation Establishment
Ma Yu
Corpse Sect disciple
Middle stage Foundation Establishment
Our Burning Fire country is full of volcanoes
and the spiritual energy is the fire element.
Prolonged exposition to it can harm cultivators.
Only the Soul Harmony Pills made from Burning Gold Fruits
can regulate our spiritual energy.
Are Burning Gold Fruits only found in the Burning Gold Mountains ?
Exactly.
When the fruits are ripe,
disciples from all 4 sects come to harvest them.
The other 3 sects have already entered,
why are we still waiting here ?
Blue mist means the fruits are ripe
and safe to harvest.
Since the mist isn't out yet,
that means there is still poisonous gas in the volcano.
We’ll be in danger
if we go down now.
Enough,
let’s go down.
Hey, you !
What ?
We only harvest 10 fruits per year
to avoid damaging the roots.
Yet you severed the entire root !?
No matter which sect you're from,
you will pay for this offense !
Die.
Damn it, damn it.
Take one more step
and you will die.
A Nascent Soul ?
Fellow cultivator, spare me.
Please have mercy.
Xu Liguo's Nascent Soul
Tian Gang Sect disciple
I’m Xu Liguo, disciple of the Tian Gang Sect of a rank 4 country.
I know I offended you earlier.
Let’s talk this through.
Please, don’t act rashly.
Cultivators stand no chance against the power of the souls here.
If wandering souls enter the mortal world,
they’ll be called devils.
Devils ?
Interesting...
What are you doing !?
I had a Nascent Soul cultivation when I had a body,
a flick of my finger could kill you !
Why isn’t he speaking ?
Is he plotting something ?
Don’t do anything reckless.
Let me tell you something,
if I could afford a Nascent Soul body
instead of this cheap Foundation Establishment one,
I would crush a Foundation Establishment brat like you !
Shut up.
Fellow cultivator !
Let’s talk this through.
If you spare me,
I’ll agree to anything !
Please calm down, fellow cultivator.
If wandering souls can devour cultivators regardless of their cultivation level,
maybe I could try to refine one here ?
If I had an army of wandering souls,
it would make my vengeance against Teng Huayuan easier.
Hey, hey, hey !
Fellow cultivator…
Please calm down, fellow cultivator !
I erased the original consciousness.
He really was at Nascent Soul...
Who are you ?
And who am I ?
Eat him.
Let me out !
You've really pissed me off !
The devil is done.
You’re courting death !
Hide inside this.
You're not allowed to come out unless I call you.
He’s even stronger now...
Lin Tao pays respects to Master.
Greetings... Senior...
Master,
here are the items you requested 3 days ago.
This is the Artifact Crafting Hall’s jade slip
with detailed artifact crafting methods.
Master, the maps are in the Scripture Pavilion’s top floor.
My cultivation was too low to access it.
10 days !
Master, give me 10 more days !
My cousin will be on duty in 10 days,
I'll ask him to make a copy.
If you succeed,
I’ll return your Soul Blood when I leave
the Burning Fire country.
Master...
I would've returned your Soul Blood now...
But this jade slip’s tracking spell
voids your achievement.
I won’t kill you.
But whether I return your Soul Blood
will depend on what you do next.
I'm glad I didn’t activate the tracking spell
to ask teacher for help.
If I did, I'd be dead already.
Senior, I couldn’t copy the Divine Path.
I tried my hardest to memorize it
but once I left the hall,
I wasn't able to remember the Divine Path.
You’re using Ma Liang’s identity
so if you’re willing
you could visit the War God Shrine
to study the Divine Path.
This Divine Path is very weird...
You don't need to be so on guard near me.
As long as you don’t provoke me,
I’ll return your Soul Blood
when I leave the country.
But if you plot against me,
don’t blame me for being ruthless.
You three may leave.
Lin Tao,
I’ll wait for you here in 10 days.
Going to the War God Shrine is too risky.
Even if these three are not scheming,
if I'm exposed for stealing this body,
I'll be in trouble.
Little friend...
Will you give me my disciple's Soul Blood ?
Feng Luan
War God Shrine Ancestor
Early stage Nascent Soul
Wang Lin says he reached Middle stage Foundation Establishment with this body but he was showed a few episodes before as Late stage Foundation Establishment in his character card. That is because his body and soul's cultivations are not synchronized. In normal circumstances, the body and the soul should be the same level but here Wang Lin's soul became a Soul Devourer and devoured wandering souls during hundreds of years so his soul's cultivation reached Late stage. Now that he has cultivated anew (he started from zero and it took 1 year outside but 10 times as much inside the Heaven Defying Bead), his body is at Middle stage Foundation Establishment.
The Corpse Sect is a tentacular organization that has branches everywhere to sell bodies to cultivators. So this Corpse Sect is not the same as the one in Zhao. In fact, all Corpse Sects on this planet are branches of the real Corpse Sect.
I've been walking this path for endless years
just to catch a glimpse of your silhouette.
Is it the compass of fate
that wrote this outcome for us ?
The heavens want to erase your existence,
that's the obsession guiding me.
Is this the path to uncover
truths from falsehoods ?
In a world of murk and shadow,
only the flame of truth can light the way.
Look at them all,
being carried by the waves.
being drowned.
I don't want to believe in whoever decides fate,
I will let the world refine my soul.
So what if I become an Immortal and defy the heavens ?
I will fight.
I'll break through the abyss of despair
to finally learn who I really am.
My body is stained by the bloody color of slaughter,
I embrace this obsession.
I won't glance back at the wasteland I left behind.
Even if this suffering shatters my soul
and I'm reborn countless times in hell,
I'll still fight.
It's hard to avoid loneliness
when you are above everyone else.
Can a moth that has witnessed the flames of a Suzaku
be afraid of a firefly ?